# **LUSAYO NYONDO**

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Location: Blantyre, Malawi

Website:

https://lusayonyondo.pythonanywhere.com

Email: lusayohendy@gmail.com

LinkedIn: @lusayo-nyondo-932a6117

Skype: live:.cid.73bfe4ba446dab7d

Github: https://github.com/lusayo-nyondo

Phone number: +265 99 757 85 23 (Available on WhatsApp)

#### WORK SUMMARY

Systems Administration (Linux and Windows)

Web Development (Full-Stack)

**Customer Support** 

**IT Support** 

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a detail-oriented IT support professional transitioning to web development with a strong focus on Django and Python.

#### **PROJECTS**

Here are some of the projects I've worked on. You can also view these on my portfolio website:

https://lusayonyondo.pythonanywhere.com.

## Transcription Business Web Application

https://github.com/lusayo-nyondo/transcriptva

- Bootstrap.
- HTML/CSS.
- React.
- Django REST Framework.

### Personal Portfolio Web Application

https://lusayonyondo.pythonanywhere.com

- Python Django.
- Tailwind CSS.
- Flow bite.
- Alpine JS.
- SQLite.
- Wagtail.

## Job Posting Platform

https://gigsandcareers.com

- WordPress.
- jQuery.
- PHP.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### IT Support Technician (Level 2)

Geeker | April 2023 - June 2024

- Providing remote support to international clients for IT related issues.
- Helping clients with troubleshooting and setting up networks.
- Providing remote support with Any Desk and custom caller software.

### Systems Administrator

People's Trading Center | Sept 2019 - April 2023

- Maintaining the availability of Linux application and database servers for an integrated Point of Sales system across over 50 sites.
- Implementing utility and servicing scripts using bash and PowerShell to expedite and automate certain processes in the server eco-system.
- Managing IBM DB2, MySQL, and MSSQL databases.
- Profiling databases to develop web applications that provide business intelligence.
- Enterprise application development with C# and Python.
- Installing, configuring, and troubleshooting networks.

#### IT Technician

People's Trading Center | March 2018 - Sept 2019

- Submitting monthly reports of technical issues faced, along with their solutions.
- Managing collaborative support using a ticketing system.
- Extensive use of MS Office Excel to compare, transform, and summarize data.
- Communicating with customers and management frequently during the resolution of issues.
- Fixing any hardware issues that arise in devices.
- Installing, configuring, and troubleshooting networks.
- Managing antivirus installations.
- Using Zendesk to log helpdesk issues.

## Freelance Web and Application Development

Various Clients | Jan 2017 - now

- Designing and developing web applications and websites using various tools.
- Designing and developing desktop applications with C#.

#### EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

# National College of Information Technology

Advanced Diploma in Computing | February 2016 - April 2018

- Passed with a distinction.
- Final project was a mobile banking android application written in Java.
- Studied Agile Project Management, Software
  Development (Java), UI/UX Design, Web Development
  (PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript), Office Solutions
  Development (VB Script and Macro Development in MS
  Office).

#### COURSES TAKEN ONLINE:

## Digital Marketing Master Course (Udemy)

People's Trading Center | Sept 2019 - Jan 2020

- Design and manage brand identity.
- Developing targeted marketing strategies.
- Designing and deploying ads.
- Using social media marketing, YouTube, and Quora.

## Python Programming (Alison)

People's Trading Center | Nov 2019 - Dec 2019

- Developing desktop and web applications using Python.
- Django.

## Databases and T-SQL (Alison)

People's Trading Center | Feb 2020 - March 2020

- Plotting entity relationship diagrams and flow-charts to represent databases and relational activity.
- Using T-SQL with an MSSQL database backend.

### Project Management (Alison)

People's Trading Center | Apr 2020 - Apr 2020

• Working on web development projects using the Agile methodology.